MARAH SHAHIN

BE(Hons)/BCom | Engineering/Data Scientist | Machine Learning Engineer | Developer

@ marahwshahin@gmail.com

J +64 210 247 4923

London, UK

marahshahin.com

in marahshahin

Marah is an Engineer specialising in Artificial Intelligence who embodies the key mix of business and commercial skills balanced with technical and analytical backing. In recent years, Marah has been working with Generative AI specifically on AWS. She has implemented large-scale LLMs for clients that have yielded exceptional results.

EXPERIENCE

Artificial Intelligence & Data Specialist Deloitte

Feb 2022 - Mar 2024

AKL. NZ

- Took a leading role in a range of projects including machine learning, data & cloud engineering, generative AI, data governance, data visualisation, AWS, ethical AI, data analysis, and data strategy
- Led a team in building a containerised Al-driven data quality tool
- Generative AI project for large insurance company led to handling time reduced by 26% and worker satisfaction increased by 10% - Marah was the lead ML and Data Engineer
- Led 4 well-received Generative AI labs for executives in educating and solutionising Generative AI projects
- Enhanced company/team eminence through published numerous AI/ML blogs and thought leadership pieces, hosted events, and presentations related to ethical AI, risks, data modernisation in the era of AI, ML customer segmentation, MLOps/AIOps, open vs. closed source LLMs, etc
- Committed to learning completed over 12 certifications/courses.

Strategic Marketing / Junior Business Analyst Hilti

Aug 2021 – Jan 2022

AKL, NZ

- Project lead redefining customer prioritisation by developing an optimisation programme to mathematically identify the highest potential long-term customers
- Facilitated numerous workshops and training sessions for various teams socialising the newly implemented data management standards

Asset Management Engineer WSP

Nov 2018 - Nov 2019

AKL, NZ

- Project lead analysing footpath profiles to better identify trips and faults to reduce hazards and improve footpath comfort for users on wheels
- Assisted in general road engineering projects

TRAINING & CERTIFICATIONS

aws AWS Certified Machine Learning - Specialty

aws AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

aws AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

aws AWS Partner: Generative AI Essentials (Business)

aws AWS Partner: Bedrock Training

4x DeepLearning.ai Courses

4x NVIDIA AI Courses

2x Dataiku Certifications

PERSONAL PROFILE

New Zealand Citizen / Youth Mobility Visa (rights to work in the UK)

PHILOSOPHY

"Focus on making yourself better, not on thinking you are better."

SKILLS & STRENGTHS

Problem Solving Project Management Stakeholder Management Eye for detail Motivator & Leader Analytics Written & Oral Communication Python **VBA** SQL AWS SageMaker Generative Al Mathematical Modelling AWS SageMaker Machine Learning Deep Learning **Operations Research** TensorFlow **Uncertainty Quantification** SolidWorks Tableau Power BI Computational Engineering **MATLAB**

ACHIEVEMENTS



Guest Lecturer

Taught Ethical AI in a University Masters course



Optimised Road Project Prioritisation Using K-Means Clustering Implemented K-means clustering

Implemented K-means clustering to prioritise road projects, resulting in a 14% increase in efficiency and a 6% reduction in accidents



Dean's Honours List

Achieved by those attaining a GPA of over 8.25 in a given year

REFEREES

Available upon request

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

BE(Hons) Engineering Science - First Class Honours University of Auckland

Thesis title: Optimal Experimental Design for Understanding Burn Injuries, A+

Research Project completed: mathematical modelling

BCom Finance and Innovation & Entrepreneurship University of Auckland

Double major | First in class award Research Project completed: innovation & entrepreneurship

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Finance Director

New Zealand Eid Day

- Dec 2020 Ongoing
- Bi-annual free-to-attend festival attracting over 12,000 people in Auckland, and thousands across Christchurch, Wellington, and Hamilton
- Fundraised over \$10,000 in 3 days from the public to support the event
- Managing the finance team in sourcing funds and financial reporting
- Advisor to the Entertainment team
- Co-leading stalls owner & stakeholder management and coordination

Operations Manager

Football For Freedom

- Oct 2021 Ongoing
- Annual non-for-profit football tournament and festival
- Managing operations and logistics
- Stakeholder & vendor management
- Advisor to the Entertainment team

NOTABLE PROJECTS

Speed Management Plan (Land & Transport Engineers)

Wellington City Council

May 2022 - Ongoing

Role: Project Manager, Freelance Contractor

Project valued at over \$45m where 97% of Wellington roads require speed limit revision under the newly established "Land Transport Rule: Setting of Speed Limits 2022".

Responsibilities include:

- Development Communications and Engagement Plan that follows best practice framework
- Derived and proposed a mathematical model for prioritising road projects in New Zealand
- · Client & Stakeholder management and development of on-going timeline programme via Microsoft Project

MLOps and Operational Controls (Deloitte)

Large Banking Client

Jun 2022 - Oct 2022

The engagement objectives were to implement ML operational controls and Responsible AI guidelines across the bank. The controls were delivered using MLOps principles with model training, algorithm optimisation, hyper-parameter tuning and deployment being orchestrated on the AWS SageMaker platform. Marah played a key role across all project activities as a Machine Learning Engineer and Delivery support for the technical advisory stream.